math_2_part_1 = {
  "Absolute value & piecewise functions": [
      {
          "Displays of distributions": {
                "Definition": "The graph of y=|x-h|+k is the graph of y=|x| shifted h units to the right and k units up",
                "QA Queue": [
                        {
                            "Question": "The graph of y = |x| is shifted up by 4 units and to the right by 5 units. What is the equation of the new graph?",
                            "Answer": "y=|x-5|+4",
                            "Type": "Narrative",
                            "Difficulty": 4
                        }
                    ],
                "Rate": 1,
                }
      },
      {
        "Piecewise functions": {
              "Definition": "A piecewise function is a function built from pieces of different functions over different intervals.",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "h(x) = {x^3 for x ∈(−∞,0], 24/x - 1 for x ∈(0,8], (x-1)(x+3) for x∈(8,∞)}. Solve for h(-3)",
                          "Answer": "h(-3) = (-3)**3 = -27",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 4
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },

  ],
  "Quadratics: Multiplying & factoring" : [
    {
        "Multiplying monomials by polynomials": {
              "Definition": "Polynomials are sums of terms of the form k⋅xⁿ, where k is any number and n is a positive integer.",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "4m**2-3m**6+5m**4. What is the degree of the polynomial?",
                          "Answer": "6",
                          "Type": "Integer",
                          "Difficulty": 4
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
    {
      "Multiplying binomials": {
            "Definition": "We express (x-4)(x+7) as the standard trinomial x²+3x-28 and discusses how the general product (x+a)(x+b) can be written as x²+(a+b)x+a*b.",
            "QA Queue": [
                    {
                        "Question": "Expand (x+5)(x+3)",
                        "Answer": "x**2 + 8*x + 15",
                        "Type": "Narrative",
                        "Difficulty": 4
                    }
                ],
            "Rate": 1,
            }
  },
  {
    "Special products of binomials": {
          "Definition": "The 'difference of squares' pattern: (a+b)(a−b)=a^2 - b^2. Two other patterns: (a+b)^2 = a^2 + 2ab + b^2; (a-b)^2 = a^2 - 2ab + b^2",
          "QA Queue": [
                  {
                      "Question": "Expand (2x+3)^2",
                      "Answer": "x**2 + 8*x + 15",
                      "Type": "Narrative",
                      "Difficulty": 4
                  }
              ],
          "Rate": 1,
          }
    },
    {
    "Introduction to factoring": {
          "Definition": "When two or more polynomials are multiplied, we call each of these polynomials factors of the product. When two or more polynomials are multiplied, we call each of these polynomials factors of the product.",
          "QA Queue": [
                  {
                      "Question": "Karen was trying to factor 6*x**2+10. She found that the greatest common factor of these terms was 2 and made an area model. What is the width of Karen's area model?",
                      "Answer": "3x^2 + 5",
                      "Type": "Narrative",
                      "Difficulty": 4
                  }
              ],
          "Rate": 1,
          }
    },
    {
    "Factoring quadratics by grouping": {
          "Definition": "Factoring a polynomial involves writing it as a product of two or more polynomials. It reverses the process of polynomial multiplication.",
          "QA Queue": [
                  {
                      "Question": "Factor the quadratic expression completely. 15x^2−4x−4",
                      "Answer": "3x*(5x+2) - 2(5x+2) = (3x-2)(5x+2)",
                      "Type": "Narrative",
                      "Difficulty": 4
                  }
              ],
          "Rate": 1,
          }
    },
    {
    "Factoring quadratics with difference of squares": {
          "Definition": " a^2 + 2ab + b^2 = (a+b)^2;  a^2 - 2ab + b^2  = (a-b)^2. Every polynomial that is a difference of squares can be factored by applying the following formula: (a+b)(a−b)=a^2 - b^2",
          "QA Queue": [
                  {
                      "Question": "The rectangle below has an area of 121 - x^2 square meters and a length of 11 - x meters. What expression represents the width of the rectangle?",
                      "Answer": "121 - x^2 = (11-x)(11+x). Hence, the width is 11+x",
                      "Type": "Narrative",
                      "Difficulty": 4
                  }
              ],
          "Rate": 1,
          }
    },
    {
    "Factoring quadratics with perfect squares": {
          "Definition": " a^2 + 2ab + b^2 = (a+b)^2;  a^2 - 2ab + b^2  = (a-b)^2. Every polynomial that is a difference of squares can be factored by applying the following formula: (a+b)(a−b)=a^2 - b^2",
          "QA Queue": [
                  {
                      "Question": "The square below has an area of 1 + 2x + x**2 square meters. What expression represents the length of one side of the square?",
                      "Answer": "1 +2x + x**2 = (1+x)**2. Hence the length of one side of the square is 1+x",
                      "Type": "Narrative",
                      "Difficulty": 4
                  }
              ],
          "Rate": 1,
          }
    }
    ],
"Intro to parabolas": [
    {
        "x": {
              "Definition": "Graphs of quadratic functions all have the same shape which we call 'parabola.' All parabolas have shared characteristics. For example, they are all symmetric about a line that passes through their vertex.",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "A parabola intersects the x-axis at x=3 and x=9. What is the x-coordinate of the parabola's vertex?",
                          "Answer": "(3+9)/2=6",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 5
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
    {
        "Solving and graphing with factored form": {
              "Definition": "The zero product property states that if a⋅b=0 then either a or b equal zero. This basic property helps us solve equations like (x+2)(x-5)=0.",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "Find the zeros of the function. Enter the solutions from least to greatest. h(x)=(−2x+3)(−x+3)",
                          "Answer": "-2x+3=0 or -x+3=0 hence x=1.5 or x=3",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 4
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
    {
        "Solving by taking the square root": {
              "Definition": "Note that every positive number has two square roots: a positive square root and a negative square root.",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "Solve for x. (x+8)^2−2=0",
                          "Answer": "(x+8)^2=2 hence x+8=sqrt(2) or x+8=-sqrt(2) hence x=sqrt(2)-8 or x=-sqrt(2)-8",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 4
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
    {
        "Vertex form": {
              "Definition": "One of the common forms for quadratic functions is called vertex form, because it highlights the coordinates of the vertex of the function's graph.",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "An object is launched from a platform. Its height (in meters), x seconds after the launch, is modeled by: h(x)=−5(x−4)^2+180. What is the height of the object at the time of launch?",
                          "Answer": "h(0)=−5(0−4)^2+180=100",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 4
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
    {
        "Solving quadratics by factoring": {
              "Definition": "You may have also solved some quadratic equations, which include the variable raised to the second power, by taking the square root from both sides.",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "Solve for x. 5x^2+15x−50=0",
                          "Answer": "x^2+3x-10=0 hence x=2 or x=-5",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 4
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
    {
        "Completing the square": {
              "Definition": "Some quadratic expressions can be factored as perfect squares. For example, x²+6x+9=(x+3)². However, even if an expression isn't a perfect square, we can turn it into one by adding a constant number. For example, x²+6x+5 isn't a perfect square, but if we add 4 we get (x+3)². This, in essence, is the method of *completing the square*.",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "Rewrite the equation by completing the square. x^2+18x+80=0",
                          "Answer": "(x+9)^2=1",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 4
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
    {
        "Completing the square": {
              "Definition": "Sal rewrites the equation y=-5x^2-20x+15 in vertex form (by completing the square) in order to identify the vertex of the corresponding parabola.",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "An object is launched from a platform. Its height (in meters), x seconds after the launch, is modeled by: \
                          h(x)=−5x^2+20x+60. What is the height of the object at the time of launch?",
                          "Answer": "h(0)=60 => 60 meters",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 4
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
    {
        "Transforming quadratic functions": {
              "Definition": "The graph of y=(x-k)²+h is the resulting of shifting (or translating) the graph of y=x², k units to the right and h units up. For example, y=(x-3)²-4 is the result of shifting y=x² 3 units to the right and -4 units up, which is the same as 4 units down.",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "The parabola y=x**2 is shifted up by 2 units and to the right by 3 units. What is the equation of the new parabola?",
                          "Answer": "(x-3)**2+2",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 4
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    }
]
}

math_2_part_2 = {
"Irrational numbers":[
    {
        "Irrational numbers": {
              "Definition": "A rational number is any number that can be expressed as the fraction of two integers. All repeating decimals can be expressed as the fraction of two integers.",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "Is the following number rational or irrational? -11*pi",
                          "Answer": "Irrational",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 4
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
    {
        "Sums & products of rational/irrational numbers": {
              "Definition": "The sum, or the product, of any two rational numbers will always be a rational number. The product of any rational number and any irrational number will always be an irrational number. The sum of any rational number and any irrational number will always be an irrational number. The sum of any rational number and any irrational number will always be an irrational number.",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "Let a be a non-zero rational number. Is sqrt(24) + a rational or irrational?",
                          "Answer": "The sum of a rational number and an irrational number is an irrational number. Hence, sqrt(a) is irrational.",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 4
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    }
],
"Complex numbers":[
    {
        "The imaginary unit i": {
              "Definition": "We introduce the imaginary unit i, which is defined by the equation i^2=-1. The formal definition of i is i^2=-1 and not sqrt(-1)=i",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "Express the radical using the imaginary unit, i: sqrt(-100)",
                          "Answer": "sqrt(-100)=10i",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 4
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
    {
        "Complex numbers introduction": {
              "Definition": "By taking multiples of this imaginary unit, we can create infinitely many more new numbers. These are examples of imaginary numbers. However, we can go even further than that and add real numbers and imaginary numbers. These combinations are called complex numbers.",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "What type of number is 52i +7.5? Complex, Imaginary or Real",
                          "Answer": "Complex since both the real and the imaginary parts are nonzero.",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 4
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
    {
        "Adding & subtracting complex numbers": {
              "Definition": "Complex numbers can be added or subtracted by separately adding or subtracting their real and imaginary terms. To add or subtract complex numbers: Expand parentheses (attending to minus signs outside of parentheses if necessary). Combine all real terms (terms that do not contain and add or subtract them. Combine all imaginary terms (terms that contain and add or subtract them.",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "(−13+16i)−(3+4i)",
                          "Answer": "-16 +12i",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 4
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
    {
        "Multiplying complex numbers": {
              "Definition": "Complex numbers are multiplied like any two binomials.",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "Multiply and simplify the following complex numbers: (−3−i)*(3+i)",
                          "Answer": "(−3−i)*(3+i) = (−3*3)+(−3*i)+(−i*3)+(−i*i) = -8 -6i",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 4
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },

    {
        "Quadratic equations with complex solutions": {
              "Definition": "Solves the equation using the quadratic formula",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "Multiply and simplify the following complex numbers: (−3−i)*(3+i)",
                          "Answer": "We can find the solutions involves taking the square root of the discriminant, the solutions are complex if the discriminant is < 0 as it is in this case. Therefore, we will have two complex solutions.\
                          Using the quadratic formula, we have 2 solution: 1/3 +- 2*sqrt(5)/3*i",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 5
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
],
"Rational exponents and radicals":[
    {
        "Rational exponents": {
              "Definition": "x^(1/n) = nth root of x",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "Which radical expression is equivalent to x^(1/7)",
                          "Answer": "x^(1/7) = 7th root of x",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 4
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
    {
        "Properties of exponents (rational exponents)": {
              "Definition": "the expression m^(7/9) / m^(1/3) as a single exponential term m^(4/9).",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "Rewrite the expression in the form x^n: 1/(x^(1/3))",
                          "Answer": "1/(x^(2/3)) = (x^(2/3))^(-1) = x^(-2/3)",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 4
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
    {
        "Solving exponential expressions using properties of exponents": {
              "Definition": "Product of Powers. Power to a Power. Quotient of Powers. Power of a Product. Power of a Quotient.",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "Solve the exponential equation for x: 2^(8x−4)*16^(3x−5)=16^(9x+2)",
                          "Answer": "LHS = (16^(1/4))^8x−4*16^(3x−5) = 16^(5x−6) => 5x-6 = 9x+2 => x = -2",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 5
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
],
"Exponential models":[
    {
        "Interpreting the rate of change of exponential models": {
              "Definition": "general form A*B^f(t) where A is the initial quantity, B is a factor by which the quantity is multiplied over constant time intervals, and\
              f(t) is an expression in terms of t that determines those time intervals.",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "After a special medicine is introduced into a petri dish full of bacteria, the number of bacteria remaining in the dish decreases rapidly. \
                          The relationship between the elapsed time t in seconds, and the number of bacteria N(t) in the petri dish is modeled by the following function: N(t)=1000 * (1/2)^(t/5.5). The number of bacteria is halved every ? seconds?",
                          "Answer": "1/2 = (1/2)^(t/5.5) hence t = 5.5",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 5
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
]
}

math_2_part_3 = {
"Similarity":[
    {
        "Definitions of similarity": {
              "Definition": "If a sequence of  (translations, reflections, and rotations) and dilations can map circle A onto circle B, then the figures are similar.",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "Triangle A has a height of 2.5 cm and a base of 1.6 cm. The height and base of triangle B are proportional to the height and base of triangle A. Which of the following could be the height and base of triangle B if the height is 2.75?",
                          "Answer": "1.76 since 2.5/1.6 = 2.75/1.6",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 4
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
    {
        "Introduction to triangle similarity": {
              "Definition": "If we can map one figure onto the other using a sequence of rigid transformations and dilations, then the figures are similar.",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "Triangle A B C. Side A C has a side length of eight. Side length A B has a side length of five. Side length B C has a side length of seven.\
                          Triangle D E F. Side D E has a side length of ten. Side length E F has a side length of ten. Side length D F has a side length of ten. \
                          Triangle G H I. Side G H has a side length of six. Side length H I has a side length of nine. Side length G I has a side length of ten.\
                          Which triangles are similar triangle A B C?",
                          "Answer": "Neither because of using side-side-side (SSS) similarity",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 4
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
    {
        "Solving similar triangles": {
              "Definition": "Similar triangles have proportional sides.",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "Two triangles F G H and D E F. Side F G is twenty-four. Side F H is twelve. Side G H is sixteen point five. Side D E is thirty-two. Side E F is twenty-two. Side D F is p.\
                          Triangle FGH is similar to triangle DEF. Solve for p.",
                          "Answer": "p/12 = 32/24 => p = 16",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 4
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
    {
        "Angle bisector theorem": {
              "Definition": "The Angle Bisector Theorem states that when an angle in a triangle is split into two equal angles, it divides the opposite side into two parts. The ratio of these parts will be the same as the ratio of the sides next to the angle. ",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "Triangle A B C, but angle A is bisected by line segment A D, creating two new triangles, triangle A C D and triangle A B D. Point D is on Side B C. Side A C is five point eight units. Side D B is two point seven units. Side C D is two point five units. angle DAC = angle BAD. What is the length of AB",
                          "Answer": "DAB and DAC are congruent, therefore AD is the bisector of CAB. Using Angle Bisector Theorem: AB/BD = AC/CD => AB = 5.8*2.7/2.5 = 6.3",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 5
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
],
"Right triangles & trigonometry": [
    {
        "Pythagorean theorem": {
              "Definition": "The Pythagorean theorem is a^2 + b^2 = c^2 where a and b are lengths of the legs of a right triangle and c is the length of the hypotenuse. The theorem means that if we know the lengths of any two sides of a right triangle, we can find out the length of the last side. We can find right triangles all over the place—inside of prisms and pyramids, on maps when we're finding distance, even hiding inside of equilateral triangles!",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "A builder makes staircases where each step is 28cm long and rises 18cm so people don't trip. Every staircase has a stringer \
                          A certain staircase will have— a diagonal support connecting all of the steps. A certain staircase will have 6 steps. What is the length l of the stringer for this staircase? \
                          Round your answer to the nearest tenth of a centimeter.",
                          "Answer": "18^2 + 28^2 = c^2 => c = sqrt(1108) => l = 6*c ~ 199.7 cm",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 4
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
    {
        "Special right triangles": {
              "Definition": "30-60-90 and 45-45-90 are special right triangles",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "A right triangle J K L where J K is x units, J L is six square root three units, and Angle J is sixty degrees. How long is JK",
                          "Answer": "In 30-60-90 triangle, the hypotenuse is twice as long as the short leg => 2*JK = JL => x*2 = 6*sqrt(3) => JK = 3*sqrt(3)",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 4
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
    {
        "Ratios in right triangles": {
              "Definition": "In a right triangle, the hypotenuse is the longest side, an 'opposite' side is the one across from a given angle, and an 'adjacent' side is next to a given angle.",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "Triangle D E F. Side E F is six point one units. Angle F is a right angle. Angle D is the angle of reference. Side D E is six point seven units. What is the approximate angle D?",
                          "Answer": "65 degrees",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 4
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
    {
        "Introduction to the trigonometric ratios": {
              "Definition": "For an angle with measure θ in a right triangle: sin(θ) = opposite leg length / hypotenuse length, cos(θ) = adjacent leg length / hypotenuse length",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "A right triangle A B C. Angle A C B is a right angle. Angle A B C is beta. Side A C is four units. Side B C is three units. Side A B is five units. Find sin(beta).                          ",
                          "Answer": "sin(beta) = opposite leg length / hypotenuse length = AC / AB = 4/5 ",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 4
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
    {
        "Sine & cosine of complementary angles": {
              "Definition": "The sine of any angle is equal to the cosine of its complementary angle",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "A right triangle A B C. Angle A C B is a right angle. Angle A B C is fifty-five degrees. Side A C is four point nine units. Side A B is six units. Which expressions represent the length of side BC?",
                          "Answer": "6sin(35) or 6coss(55)",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 4
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
    {
        "Modeling with right triangles": {
              "Definition": "When you see an object above you, there's an angle of elevation between the horizontal and your line of sight to the object. Similarly, when you see an object below you, there's an angle of depression  between the horizontal and your line of sight to the object.",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "Galileo wanted to release a wooden ball and an iron ball from a height of 150 meters and measure the duration of their fall.He found a plane with an incline of 15 degrees that he could climb until he gets to an altitude of 150 m. How far should Galileo walk up the inclined plane? \
                          Round your final answer to the nearest hundredth.",
                          "Answer": "sin(15) = 150 / x => x = 579.56",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 4
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
],
"Solid geometry" : [
    {
        "2D vs. 3D objects": {
              "Definition": "Area is the amount of space enclosed in a 2D figure. We'll find the area of bases and cross-sections of 3D figures as a first step toward finding their volume. Also, understanding the area of cross-sections will help us relate volumes of tricky figures to the volumes of more familiar figures.\
              Volume is the amount of space enclosed in a 3D figure. We'll use the volumes of familiar solids, like right rectangular prisms, to help us find the volumes of more unusual figures, like prisms that lean to one side, all sorts of pyramids, and figures with different shapes of bases.",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "What is the one shape of cross-section we could create by slicing the sphere?",
                          "Answer": "Circle",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 5
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
    {
        "2D vs. 3D objects": {
              "Definition": "If two 2D or 3D figures have the same height and same width at every point along that height, they have the same area and volume.",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "The following figures all have the same height and same base area. A rectangular prism, an oblique rectangular prism, and a cylinder. The oblique shape leans to the right at the top. For which of the figures can we apply Cavalieri's principle to show they have the same volume?",
                          "Answer": "A, B, and C",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 4
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
    {
        "Volume and surface area": {
              "Definition": "The areas of the top and the base are simply the area of a circle: πr^2",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "What is the surface area of a cylinder with base radius 4 and height 5?",
                          "Answer": "πr^2 = π*4^2=16π",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 4
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
    {
        "Density": {
              "Definition": "Volume density is the amount of a quantity (often mass) per unit of volume. Density=Quantity/Volume. ",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "To play basketball with her friends, Evangeline needs to pump air in her ball, which is completely deflated.\
                           Before inflating it, the ball weighs 0.615 kilograms. Afterwards, it weighs 0.624 0.6240, point, 624 kilograms. \
                           The diameter of the ball is 0.24 meters. Assuming the inflated ball is perfectly spherical, what is the air density within it? \
                           Round your answer, if necessary, to the nearest hundredth.",
                          "Answer": "total quantiy = 0.624−0.615=0.009, volume = 4/3*π*radius^2= 4/3*π*(0.24/2)^2. Hence Density=Total Quantity/Volume ~ 1.24",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 5
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
]
}

math_2_part_4 = {
"Circles": [
    {
        "Arc measure": {
              "Definition": "The measure of an arc is equal to the measure of the central angle that intercepts it.",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "A circle that is centered around point P. Points A, B, C, and D all lie on this circle in a clockwise direction. Line segment B D and line segment A C are diameters of the circle. Line segments A P, B P, C P, and D P are radii of the circle. The angle A P B is a nineteen degree angle. What is the arc measure of minor arc DC in degrees?",
                          "Answer": "The measures of ∠DPC and ∠APB are congruent because they are vertical angles. Hence, minor arc DC = 19",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 4
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
    {
        "Arc length (from degrees)": {
              "Definition": "The ratio between the arc's central angle theta and 360 degree is equal to the ratio between the arc length s and the circle's circumference c",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "A circle with circumference 20 has an arc with a 72 central angle. What is the length of the arc?",
                          "Answer": "theta / 360 = s / c => 72 / 360 = s / 20 => s = 4",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 4
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
    {
        "Introduction to radians": {
              "Definition": "An angle can be measured in degrees or in radians. A circle can be divided into 360 degree or 2π radians",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "Convert the angle θ = 5π/12 radians to degrees",
                          "Answer": "angle in degree = 360 / 2π * 5π/12 = 75 degrees",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 4
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
    {
        "Arc length (from radians)": {
              "Definition": "A central angle theta measured in radians tells us how many times the radius fits into the arc: arc length / radius = theta",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "A circle that is centered around point P. Points A, B, and C are on the circle and line segment A C is a diameter. Line segments A P, B P and C P are radii of the circle that are twenty-five units long. Angle A P B is three over ten pi. What is the exact length of BCA",
                          "Answer": "Circuference = 2πr = 50π; mBCA = 2π - 3/10*π = 17π/10; arc_length/circuference = arc_measure/radians in a circle => arc length = 85π/2",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 5
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
    {
        "Sectors": {
              "Definition": "The ratio between the area of a sector and the area of the whole circle is proportional to the ratio between the sector's central angle and the central angle of the whole circle",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "A circle with a radius of eight centimeters. A sector is highlighted. The area of the sector is fifty-six pi centimeters squared. What is the central angle measure of the sector in radians?",
                          "Answer": "area = π8^2 = 64π; theta / 2π = 56π / 64π => theta = 7π/4",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 5
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
    {
        "Inscribed angles": {
              "Definition": "An inscribed angle is half of a central angle that subtends the same arc",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "A circle centered at point P. Points A, B, and C all lie on the circle in a clockwise direction so that angle A B C is inscribed in the circle and intercepts arc A C. Line segments P C and A P are radii. Line segment P C is twelve units. The arc length of arc A C is sixty-eight pi divided by fifteen units. What is the measure of ABC in degrees?",
                          "Answer": "arc_length/circuference = arc_measure/degrees in a circle => (68π/15)/24π = arc_measure / 360 => measure of ABC = 68",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 4
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
    {
        "Properties of tangents": {
              "Definition": "Any two segments tangent to a circle from a common endpoint are congruent.",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "A circle centered around point P. The circle is inscribed inside quadrilateral A B C D so that each side is tangent to the circle. Side C D is eleven point one units. From the tangent point on side B C to point C is eight units. From the tangent point on side A B to point B is three point one units. From the tangent point on side A D to point A is eight units. What is the perimeter of the quadrilateral?",
                          "Answer": "Any two segments tangent to a circle from a common endpoint are congruent. Hence we can identify three other segments which are 8 or 3.1 => perimeter = 8 + 3.1 + 8 + 3.1 + 8 + 3.1 + 8 + 3.1 = 44.4",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 4
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
],
"Conic sections":[
    {
        "Standard equation of a circle": {
              "Definition": "Given a circle on the coordinate plane, Sal finds its standard equation, which is an equation in the form (x-a)²+(y-b)²=r²",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "The equation of a circle is (x+7)²+(y+8)²=4/9. What is its center and radius?",
                          "Answer": "center = (-7,-8) and radius = sqrt(4/9)=2/3",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 4
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
    {
        "Expanded equation of a circle": {
              "Definition": "The expanded form equation can be transformed into standard form:",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "A certain circle can be represented by the following equation: x^2+y^2−18x+20y+177=0. What is the center of this circle ?",
                          "Answer": "x^2+y^2−18x+20y+177=0 <=> (x−9)^2+(y-(-10))^2=4 => center: (9,-10)",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 4
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
    {
        "Focus & directrix of a parabola": {
              "Definition": "A parabola is the set of all points equidistant from a point (called the 'focus') and a line (called the 'directrix')",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "Write the equation for a parabola with a focus at (-8,-1) and a directrix at y=-4",
                          "Answer": "Dist((x,y), (-8,-1)) = Dist((x,y), y=-4) => (x+8)^2+(y+1)^2 = (y+4)^2 => y = (x+8)^2/6 - 5/2",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 5
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
],
"Probability":[
    {
        "Probability basics": {
              "Definition": "Probability is simply how likely something is to happen.",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "Harry and Larry are having a barbecue dinner. The probability of Harry staining his shirt during the dinner is 1/5. The probability of Larry staining his shirt during the dinner is 15%. Who will be more likely to stain his shirt?",
                          "Answer": "Harry",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 4
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
    {
        "Counting with combinations": {
              "Definition": "We can find the number of different groups using the combination formula for selecting r objects from n total objects: nCr = n!/((n-r)!*r!)",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "Mackenzie's ice cream shop lets customers choose 2 toppings from the list below to add to their ice cream: Hot fudge, Caramel, Whipped cream, Sprinkles , Strawberries, Chocolate chips ​ ​",
                          "Answer": "6C2 = 15",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 4
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
    {
        "Probability with counting, permutations, combinations": {
              "Definition": "we can use permutations and combinations to help us find the counts in the numerator and/or denominator. The most important thing is to distinguish whether or not order matters in the given scenario: If order matters, we use permutations. If order doesn't matter, we use combinations.",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "Tobin's friend Rose claims that she can read minds. To test Rose's abilities, Tobin draws 3 cards without replacement from a standard deck of 52 playing cards. Tobin asks Rose to identify each of the 3 cards she drew in order. Assume that Rose has no special abilities and is randomly guessing the cards. What is the probability that Rose identifies all 3 cards in the correct order?",
                          "Answer": "P = # of correct arrangements / # of ways to draw 3 cards = 1/(52P3)",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 4
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },

    {
        "Multiplication rule for independent events": {
              "Definition": "If 2 events are independent, the probability that 2 events occur is the product of the probabilities of 2 events",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "Captain Gabriela has a ship, the H.M.S. Khan. The ship is two furlongs from the dread pirate Daniel and his merciless band of thieves. \
                          The Captain has probability 1/2 of hitting the pirate ship. The pirate only has one good eye, so he hits the Captain's ship with probability 1/3",
                          "Answer": "(1-1/2)*(1-1/3)=1/3",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 4
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
    {
        "Multiplication rule for dependent events": {
              "Definition": "In probability, if one event affects the outcome of the other event, is called a dependent event",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "In a class of 10, there are 2 students who forgot their lunch. If the teacher chooses 2 students, what is the probability that both of them forgot their lunch?",
                          "Answer": "2/10*1/9=1/45",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 4
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
    {
        "Addition rule for probability": {
              "Definition": "Addition Rule of Probability states that given two events A and B: P(A or B)=P(A)+P(B)−P(A and B)",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "30 students in a high school health class are asked to write down what foods they ate last week.\
                           Of the 30 students, 10 write tacos, 18 write pizza, and 5 write both tacos and pizza. Using this information, answer each of the following questions. \
                          Let T be the event that randomly selected student writes tacos and P be the event that a randomly selected student writes pizza. Wwhat is P(T or P)",
                          "Answer": "P(T)+P(P)−P(T and P) = 10/30 + 18/30 - 5/30 = 23/30",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 5
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
    {
        "Conditional probability": {
              "Definition": "If A and B are two events in a sample space S, then the conditional probability of A given B is defined as P(A|B)=P(A∩B)P(B), when P(B)>0",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "In general, P(A ∣ B)=P(B ∣ A) You can reverse the order and the probability is the same either way. True or False",
                          "Answer": "False",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 5
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
    {
        "Expected value": {
              "Definition": "Expected value uses probability to tell us what outcomes to expect in the long run.",
              "QA Queue": [
                      {
                          "Question": "A board game uses the spinner shown below to determine how many spaces a player will move forward on each turn. The probability is 1/2 that the player moves forward 1 space, and moving forward 2 or 3 spaces each have 1/4 probability. What is the expected value for the number of spaces a player moves forward on a turn? If necessary, round your answer to the nearest hundredth.",
                          "Answer": "expected value = 1/2*(P_1_space) + 1/4*(P_2_space) + 1/4*(P_3_space) = 1/2 + 1/2 + 3/4 = 1.75",
                          "Type": "Narrative",
                          "Difficulty": 5
                      }
                  ],
              "Rate": 1,
              }
    },
]
}